Cyberspace Communications 501(c)3 Application

This page contains a representation of Cyberspace Communications Inc's application for federal 501(c)3 tax-exempt status. The IRS granted Cyberspace Communications this status on July 13, 1998. Though the author has done his best to accurately reproduce the actual form submitted, this version should not be treated as authoritive.

On the actual form, most of the narrative portions appear as attachments at the end of the form. In this version, all attachments have been inserted into the appropriate places in the form.

The real IRS 1023 form and its instructions, as well as publication 557, are available from IRS Forms and Publications.

- Jan Wolter
5/21/98

Page 1

Form 1023
(Rev. April 1996)
Department of Treasury
Internal Revenue Service | Application for Recognition of Exemption
Under Section 501(c)3 of the Internal Revenue Code | OMB No. 1545-0056

If exempt status is
approve, this
application will be open
for public inspection.

Read the instructions for each Part carefully.
A User Fee must be attached to this document
If the required information and appropriate documents are not submitted along with Form 8718 (with payment of the appropriate user fee), the application may be returned to you.
Complete the Procedure Checklist on page 7 of the instructions

Part I: Identification of Applicant
1a Full name of organization (as shown in organizating document)
Cyberspace Communications Incorporated | 2 Employer identifcation number (EIN)
XX-XXXXXXX
1b c/o Name (if applicable)
Jan Wolter | 3 Name and telephone number of person
to be contacted if additional information
is needed
Jan Wolter
(313) 995-6716
1c Address (number and street)
406 West Liberty
1d City or town, state, and ZIP code
Ann Arbor, MI 48103-4343 | 4 Month the annual accounting period ends
December
5 Date incorporated or formed
6/21/1991 | 6 Activity codes (see page 3 of instructions.)
123   560 | 7 Check here if applying under section:
a [  ] 501(e)   b [  ] 501(f)   c [  ] 501(k)

8 Did the organization previously apply for recognition of exemption under this Code section or any other section of the code?
If "Yes," attach an explanation. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

9 Is the organization required to file Form 990 (or Form 990-EZ)?
If "No," attach an explanation (see page 3 of the Specific Instructions). | [ ] N/A  [ ] Yes  [X] No

Cyberspace Communications has never been required to file form 990 because its gross annual receipts have always been well below $25,000.

10 Has the organization filed Federal income tax or exempt organization information returns?
If "Yes," state the form numbers, years filed, and the Internal Revenue office where filed. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

11 Check the box for the type of organization. ATTACH A CONFORMED COPY OF THE CORRESPONDING ORGANIZING DOCUMENTS TO THE APPLICATION BEFORE MAILING. (See Specific Instructions for Part I, Line 11, on page 3.) Get Pub 557, Tax-Exempt Status for Your Organization, for examples of organizational documents.)

a | [X] Corporation- | Attach a copy of the Articles of Incorporation (including amendments and restatements) showing approval by the appropriate state official; also include a copy of the bylaws.

Cyberspace Communications Articles of Incorporation
Cyberspace Communications Bylaws

b | [ ] Trust- | Attach a copy of the Trust Indenture or Agreement, including all appropriate signatures and dates.
c | [ ] Association- | Attach a copy of the Articles of Association, Constitution, or other creating document, with a declaration (see instructions) or other evidence the organization was formed by adoption of the document by more than one persn; also include a copy of the bylaws.

If the organization is a corporation or an unincorporated association that has not yet adopted bylaws, check here   [ ]

I declare under the penalties of perjury that I am authorized to sign this appication on behalf of the above organization and that I have examined this application, including the accompanying schedules and attachements, and that to the best of my knowledge it is true, correct, and complete.

Please
Sign
Here
| Jan Wolter | President | 4/28/98
(Signature) | (Title or authority of signer) | (Date)

Page 2

Part II: Activities and Operational Information

1 Provide a detailed narrative description of all the activities of the organization--past, present, and planned. Do not merely refer to or repeat the language in the organizational document. List each activity separately in the order of importance based on the relative time and other resources devoted to the activity. Indicate the percentage of time for each activity. Each description should include, as a minimum, the following: (a) a detailed description of the activity including its purpose and how each activity furthers your exempt purpose; (b) when the activity was or will be initiated; (c) where and by whom the activity will be conducted.

Cyberspace Communications has activities in the following four areas:

A. Maintaining and developing Grex. The primary activity of Cyberspace Communications, occupying about 95% of our organization's time, is the operation of a public-access computer system called "Grex" (after the Latin word for "group"). This computer system is currently housed in a rented room at [a location] in Ann Arbor and has been in continuous operation since June of 1991. It is operated by a volunteer staff under the direction of the Cyberspace Communications board of directors and currently has about 18,000 registered users. Grex provides a wide range of services to the community that further the mission of Cyberspace Communications:

A bank of dial-in modem lines in Ann Arbor (at 734-761-3000) and an Internet connection (at grex.cyberspace.org) are available.

These allow people in the Ann Arbor area to easily access our service (through the dial-in lines), but also allows access by people all over the world (through the Internet connection). Maintaining our own direct dial-in service means that even people with only "obsolete" computers (readily available for less than $40) can easily use all our services.

A simple registration process enables users coming in from either the dial-in lines or the Internet to create Grex accounts for themselves. This process is designed to be as barrier-free as possible, encouraging the widest possible range of users to access our system. Users are not required to pay any fees, nor are they required to give any information about themselves. Accounts are created immediately and there is no delay in gaining access.

This registration process is the key to our charitable mission. It enables a wide variety of people who could not otherwise afford Internet services to use our system. We serve many poor people as well as other users who could not justify paying commercial rates for services they only use occasionally. People from all over the world connect over the Internet to access services that are prohibitively expensive or completely unavailable in their own countries.

Our open registration policy also supports our educational mission. Our free and anonymous access means we have a very large population of young users, as well as many older users who want to experiment with the Internet without paying to do so.

We produce a variety of instructional materials, both printed and electronic, designed to help people learn to use Grex. We answer hundreds of user questions a week through E-mail and our on-line live help facility.

Educating users in the use of Grex is a necessary component of both our educational and charitable mission.

Grex hosts electronic conferences on more than 100 topics, all of which are open to all of our users. Typical conference topics include music, the arts, writing, consumer information, housing, finance, small business, philosophy, living with disabilities, men's and women's issues, parenting, pets, computers hardware and software, nature, cyberpunk, and role playing games. There are also rather non-topical "creative" conferences, and a general discussion area called "agora". All Cyberspace Communications policies are discussed and developed in a public conference called "coop".

These discussion forums are the key to our educational mission. The only direct teaching done by Cyberspace Communications is focused on how to use our system. Our broader educational mission is served by providing and maintaining these discussion forums where the content is entirely generated by the users. The wide range of users attracted by our open access policy ensures a wide range of knowledge and opinion. On-line forums are very effective in drawing people with diverse backgrounds into shared discussions.

Cyberspace Communications does not attempt to limit discussion to "serious" topics. We believe that simply socializing on line can greatly aid the personal development of many of our young users. On-line forums can be a very non-threatening environment in which to learn social skills, up to and including those needed to democratically run a community service, and to gain proficiency in written communications.

Grex provides a range of basic Internet services, allowing all users to send and receive E-mail, surf the web, and publish their own web pages. In all cases, our service is of much lower quality than commercial servers, using older, non-graphical user interfaces and a rather slow Internet connection, but it is nevertheless usable.

Providing these services for free is an important part of our charitable mission, and helping people learn their use is an important part of our educational mission.

Grex runs on a sophisticated Unix system, to which all users are given full access. As a volunteer operation, Cyberspace Communications constantly works to recruit and train new people to help run Grex. For several people, experience using or running Grex has been a vital step in launching or advancing careers in computing.
Out of necessity, Grex's staff must be very active in policing the system, ensuring that hostile users do not abuse our service to the detriment of our other users or of other systems on the Internet. However, we recognize that many of the "problem" users are, in fact, young people who need guidance to become good citizens of the net, so we strive to respond to problems in an educational rather than punitive manner. We believe we have had a very good success rate with this.

B. Publicizing the services offered through Grex. Grex is well-established and well-known and word- of-mouth advertising already brings us more users than we can easily handle, so publicity currently accounts for under 2% of our time. We do do some publicity focused on Ann Arbor area users, and we increase our publicity whenever we expand our resources.

C. Fundraising to support Grex. We are primarily funded by donations from our users. We have not been very active in seeking outside funding lest we lose the sense of being a "grass roots" organization, nor do we like to pressure our users for money very much lest we scare off people who cannot afford to pay. Thus our fundraising is very passive, consuming less than 2% of our time.

D. Repair and distribution of used computers. In the past Cyberspace Communications has coordinated the repair and distribution of second-hand computers to people who need them to access Grex and lacked the money or expertise to obtain them. There has been little demand for this to date, so this activity has accounted for less than 1% of our time.

Users of Grex engage in a wide range of off-line social activities, but Cyberspace Communications itself has very little involvement in organizing or funding these activities.

2 What are or will be the organization's sources of financial support? List in order of size.

Membership dues.
Other individual and corporate donations of money, goods, and services.
Special fundraising events (charity auctions, etc.).
Sale of promotional items (T-shirts, etc.).

3 Describe the organization's fundraising program, both actual and planned and explain to what extent it has been put into effect. Include details of fundraising activities such as selective mailings, formation of fundraising committees, use of volunteers or professional fund raisers, etc. Attach representative copies of soliticitions for financial support.

Cyberspace Communications is not very active in fundraising. It is primarily supported by voluntary donations from individual users. We encourage users interested in supporting Grex to become members. Various messages on the system encourage users to join, and we occasionally ask users to become members, but solicitations for donations are generally kept low key to avoid making users who cannot pay feel unwelcome. About 100 of our 18,000 users are members.

We also hold occasional on-line fundraisers to help purchase new equipment, and periodically we hold charity auctions where donated goods and services are auctioned off on-line. We also raise some money by selling Grex T-shirts, coffee mugs, mouse pads, and similar items.

Cyberspace Communications has never been very active in seeking government or corporate funding. We have asked local Internet providers to donate net connectivity, and may in the future solicit donations of equipment and services. Though we are less likely to seek monetary support in the form of corporate or government grants, this possibility has not been excluded.

Page 3

Part II: Activities and Operational Information (Continued)

3 Give the following information about the organization's governing body:

a Names, addresses, and titles of officers, directors, trustees, etc.

Jan Wolter (board & president) 406 W. Liberty, Ann Arbor, MI
Mark Conger (board & treasurer) 309 W. Hoover #1, Ann Arbor, MI
Scott Helmke (board & secretary) 1121 Bydding, Ann Arbor, MI
Stephen C. Gibbard (board) 1058 Island Drive Ct. #105, Ann Arbor, MI
Daniel Gryniewicz (board) 2101 Thaler Ave., Ann Arbor, MI
Valerie Mates (board) 406 W. Liberty, Ann Arbor, MI
Misti A. Tucker (board) 2523 Torrey Ave., Ann Arbor, MI

| b Annual compensation

All board members
are volunteers
and receive no
compensation

c Do any of the above persons serve as members of the governing board by reason of being public officials or being appointed by public officials?
If "Yes," name those persons and explain the basis of their selection or appointment. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

d Are any members of the organization's governing body "disqualified persons" with respect to the organization (other than by reason of being a member of the governing body) or do any of the members have either a business or family relationship with "disqualied persons"? (See Specific Instructions for Part II, Line 4d, on page 3.)
If "Yes," explain. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

5 Does the organization control or is it controlled by any other organization? | [ ] Yes  [X] No
Is the organization the outgrowth of (or successor to) another organization, or does it have a special relationship with another organization by reason of interlocking directorates or other factors? | [ ] Yes  [X] No
If either of these questions is answered "Yes," explain.

6 Does or will the organization directly or indirectly engage in any of the following transactions with any political organization or other exempt organization (other than a 501(c)(3) organization): (a) grants; (b) purchases or sales of assets; (c) rental of facilities or equipment; (d) loans or loan guarantees; (e) reimbursement arrangements; (f) preformance of services, membership, or fundraising solicitation; (g) sharing of facilities, equipment, mailing lists or other assets, or paid employees?
If "Yes," explain fully and identify the other organizations involved. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

7 Is the organization financially accountable to any other organization?
If "Yes," explain and idenfity the organization. Include details concerning accountability or attach copies of reports if any have been submitted. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

Page 4

Part II: Activities and Operational Information (Continued)

8 What assets does the organization have that are used in the performance of its exempt function? (Do not include property producing investment income.) If any assets are not fully operation, explain their status, what additional steps remain to be completed, and when such final steps will be taken. If "None," indicate "N/A."

Cyberspace Communications has the following assets:

1 | Sun 4/670 dual-processor computer with 6Gig disk. Main Grex computer. Operational.
1 | Sun 4/260 computer with 2Gig disk. Backup computer. Operational.
16 | Modems. For dial-in lines. Operational.
2 | Chase IOLan terminal servers. To interface the modems to Grex. Operational.
2 | Ascend P50 ISDN routers. To interface Grex to the Internet. Operational.
1 | 486 computer. Old router, now used for network administration. Operational.
1 | Pentium computer. Future mail server. Awaiting funds to purchase a disk.
| A desk, various chairs and shelves and office fixtures.
| Various spare parts and tools.

9 Will the organization be the beneficiary of tax-exempt bond financing within the next 2 years? | [ ] Yes  [X] No

10a Will any of the organization's facilities or operations be managed by another organization or individual under a contractual agreement? | [ ] Yes  [X] No
b Is the organization a party to any leases? | [X] Yes  [ ] No

If either of these questions is answered "Yes" attach a copy of the contracts and explain the relationship between the applicant and the other parties.

Cyberspace Communications rents a small room for its computer equipment at [a location] from Washtenaw Reality. No one associated with Washtenaw Reality has any connection to Cyberspace Communications beyond this rental agreement. A copy of the lease, which is somewhat informal, is on the next page.

Note: I haven't typed the lease into the HTML version of this document yet. - jan

11 Is the organization a membership organization? | [X] Yes  [ ] No

If "Yes," complete the following:

a Describe the organization's membership requirements and attach a schedule of membership fees and dues.

Membership costs $6 a month, or $60 a year. Members are also asked to provide some form of ID, which is not otherwise required from our users.

b Describe the organizations present and proposed efforts to attract members and attach a copy of any descriptive literature or promotional material used for this purpose.

The web pages and login screens on Grex contain notices asking users to consider becoming members. Membership is often mentioned in our public discussion forums, especially those relating to the administration of the system. The following text is displayed to users who ask for more information on-line:

Thanks for asking how to support Grex.  You don't have to pay to use Grex, 
but users' donations pay all the bills.  If users don't support Grex, it 
will go away.  Please support this valuable community resource.

The best way to support Grex is to become a member.  Members get to:
  - vote in Grex elections (if you've paid for three months or more)
  - receive the 'Wizard in Training' manual free (again with 3 months)
  - use our internet link.

Organizations may also support Grex and be recognized as Institutional 
members.  Institutional members have the same privileges as regular 
members, except the right to vote.

The minimum membership dues donation - Individual or Institutional - is 
$6/month or $60/year (US currency). Send a personal check or enclose a copy 
of other ID with your dues.  Other donations at any time from members or 
non-members are welcome.  Write to 'aruba' for more info.  Send cash, 
checks or money orders to:

Cyberspace Communications Inc
P.O. Box 4432
Ann Arbor, MI 48106-4432

Cyberspace Communications occasionally circulates fliers and places advertisements in various publications, but these are primarily designed to attract users to the system, not to win new members.

c What benefits do (or will) the members receive in exchange for their payments?

Individual members receive the right to vote in board elections and run for board positions. They may call for and vote in referenda.

Institutional members do not have the right to vote.

All members may receive, if they like, a copy of a 23-page photocopied user manual. This is also available to all users for our cost of one dollar.

Members do not receive any special privileges in connecting to Grex or using any services on Grex itself. However, they do have have expanded privileges in connecting from Grex to other computers on the Internet. The most important Internet services, E-mail and web browsing, are free to all Grex users, but only members can use their Grex accounts to do such things as use a 'telnet' program to log into another system on the net, or use an 'ftp' program to transfer files to and from other systems on the net, or use an 'irc' program to access the Internet Relay Chat. These are services that we cannot offer to thousands of anonymous users because we lack the resources to support them, and, in some cases, because they would enable hackers to use our system as a safe base for attacking other systems on the Internet. Since these services are not of much interest to most people and are provided with much better quality by even the least expensive commercial Internet service providers, they do not seem to be a large incentive for most of our members.

12a If the organization provides benefits, services, or products, are the recipients required, or will they be required, to pay for them?
If "Yes," explain how the charges are determined and attach a copy of the current fee schedule. | [X] Yes  [ ] No

Only as described in the response to item 11c above.

b Does or will the organization limit its benefits, services, or products to specific individuals or classes of individuals?
If "Yes," explain how the recipients or beneficiaries are or will be selected. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

13 Does or will the organization attempt to influence legislation?
If "Yes," explain. Also give an estimate of the percentage of the organization's time and funds that it devotes or plans to devote to this activity. | [X] Yes  [ ] No

Cyberspace Communications does not and will not attempt to influence legislation as a substantial activity. Legislation is often discussed on our system by our users, but Cyberspace Communications does not limit participation in or otherwise attempt to influence the content of such discussions. Cyberspace Communications may, in the case of legislation in areas that would directly impact our ability to perform our mission (e.g., Internet free speech and privacy), take a public stance on issues, but this would be unusual and never a substantial part of our activities. Our only such action to date was supporting last year's "blue ribbon campaign" against the "Communications Decency Act" by temporarily blacking out our web page. Given the uncertain future of Internet legislation, the possibility that Cyberspace Communications would find it necessary to make more substantial lobbying efforts, as allowed for under section 501(h), cannot be excluded, but our plan and firm expectation is that lobbying will continue to account for less than a hundredth of one percent of our activities.

14 Does or will the organization intervene in any way in political campaigns, including publication or distribution of statements?
If "Yes," explain fully. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

Although Cyberspace Communications does not and will not support any candidate for any office, any of our users may publish, distribute and discuss campaign materials through our system. Cyberspace Communications does not limit participation in or otherwise attempt to influence the content of such discussions, and people of all views would be welcome to join in.

Page 5

Part III: Technical Requirements

1 Are you filing Form 1023 within 15 months from the end of the month in which your organization was created or formed?
If you answer "Yes," do not answer questions on lines 2 through 7 below. | [ ] Yes  [X] No

2 If one of the exceptions to the 15-month filing requirement shown below applies, check the appropriate box and proceed to question 8.

Exceptions-You are not required to file an exemption application within 15 months if the organization:

[ ] | a | Is a church, interchurch organization of local units of a church, a confention or association of churches, or an integrated auxiliary of a church. See Specific Instructions, Line 2a, on page 4.
[ ] | b | Is not a private foundation and normally has gross receipts of not more than $5,000 in each tax year; or
[ ] | c | Is a subordinate organization covered by a group exemption letter, but only if the parent or supervisory organization timely submitted a otice covering the subordinate.

3 If the organization does not meet any of the expections on line 2 above, are you filing Form 1023 within 27 months from the end of the month in which the organization was created or formed?

If "Yes," your organization qualifies under section 4.01 of Rev. Proc. 92-85, 1992-2 C.B. 490 for an automatic 12-month extension of the 15-month filing requirement. Do not answer questions 4 through 7.

If "No," answer question 4.

| [ ] Yes  [X] No

4 If you answer "No," to question 3, has the organization been contacted by the IRS regarding its failure to file Form 1023 within 27 months from the end of the month in which the organization was created or formed?

If "No," your organization is requesting an extension of time to apply under the "reasonable action and good faith" requirements of section 5.01 of Rev. Proc. 92-85. Do not answer questions 5 through 7.

If "Yes," answer question 5.

| [ ] Yes  [X] No

5 If you answer "Yes," to question 4, does the organization wish to request relief from the 15-month filing requirement?

If "Yes," give the reasons for not filing this application prior to being contacted by the IRS. See Specific Instructions, Line 5 on page 4, before completing this item. Do not answer questions 6 and 7.

If "No," answer question 6.

| [ ] Yes  [ ] No

6 If you answer "No" to question 5, your organization's qualification as a section 501(c)(3) organization can be recognized only from the date this application is filed with your key District Director. Therefore, do you want us to consider this application as a request of exemption as a section 501(c)(3) organization from the date the application is received and not retroactively to the date the organization was created or formed? | [ ] Yes  [ ] No

7 If you answer "Yes" to question 6 above and wish to request recognition of section 501(c)(4) status for the period beginning with the date the organization was formed and ending with the date the Form 1023 application was received (the effective data of the organization's section 501(c)(3) status), check here > [ ] and attach a completed page 1 of Form 1024 to this application.

Page 6

Part III: Technical Requirements (Continued)

8 Is the organization a private foundation?

[ ] | Yes | (answer question 9.)
[X] | No | (answer question 10 and proceed as instructed.)

9 If you answered "Yes" to question 8, does the organization claim to be a private operating foundation?

[ ] | Yes | (Complete Schedule E.)
[ ] | No |

10 If you answer "No" to question 8, indeicate the public charity classification the organization is requesting by checking the box below that most appropriatedly applies:

THE ORGANIZATION IS NOT A PRIVATE FOUNDATION BECAUSE IT QUALIFIES:

a [ ] | As a church or a convention or association of churches
(CHURCHES MUST COMPLETE SCHEDULE A.) | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(i)
b [ ] | As a school (MUST COMPLETE SCHEDULE B.) | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(ii)
c [ ] | As a hospital or cooperative hospital service organization, or a medical research organization operated with a hospital (MUST COMPLETE SCHEDULE C.) | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(iii)
d [ ] | As a governmental unit described in section 170(c)(1). | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(v)
e [ ] | As being operated solely for the benefit of, or in connection with, one or more of the organizations described in a through d, g, h, or i
(MUST COMPLETE SCHEDULE D.) | Sections 509(a)(3)
f [ ] | As being organized and operated exclusively for testing for public safety. | Sections 509(a)(4)
g [ ] | As being operated for the benefit of a college or university that is owned or operated by a governmental unit. | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(iv)
h [X] | As receiving a substantial part of its support in the form of contributions from publicly supported organizations, from a governmental unit, or from the general public. | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(vi)
i [ ] | As normally receiving not more than one-third of its support from gross investment income and more than one-third of its support from contributions, membership fees, and gross receipts from activities related to its exempt functions (subject to certain exclusions). | Sections 509(a)(2)
j [ ] | The organization is a publicly supported organization but is not sure whether it meets the public support test of block h or block i. The organization would like the IRS to decide the proper classification. | Sections 509(a)(1)
and 170(b)(1)(A)(vi)
or Sections 509(a)(2)

If you checked one of the boxes a through f in question 10, go to question
15. If you checked box g in question 10, go to questions 12 and 13.
If you checked box h, i, or j, in question 10, go to questions 11.

Page 7

Part III: Technical Requirements (Continued)

11 If you checked box h, i, or j in question 10, has the organization completed a tax year of at least 8 months?

[X] | Yes-Indicate whether you are requesting:
| [X] A definitive ruling (Answer questions 12 through 15.)
| [ ] An advance ruling (Answer questions 12 through 15 and attach two Forms 872-C completed and signed.)
[ ] | No-You must request an advance ruling by completeing and signing two Forms 872-C and attaching them to the application.

12 If the organization received any unusual grants during the tax years shown in Part IV-A, attach a list for each year showing the name of the contributor; the date and amount of the grant; and a breif description of the nature of the grant.

N/A

13 If you are requesting a definitive ruling under sections 170(b)(1)(A)(iv) or (vi), check here > [X] and:

a Enter 2% of line 8, column (e), Total, of Part IV-A. | 476.17
b Attach a list showing the name and amount contributed by each person (other than a government unit or a "publicly supported" organization) whose total gifts, grants, contributions, etc., were more than the amount entered on line 13a above.

The following is a complete list of people have contributed more than $476.17 to Cyberspace Communications since 1/1/95:

    Jan Wolter           $795.18
    Rob Argyropolous     $551.03

14 If you are requesting a definitive ruling under section 509(a)(2), check here > [ ] and:

a For each of the years included on lines 1, 2, and 9 of Part IV-A, attach a list showing the name of and the amount received from each "disqualified person." (For a definition of "disqualified person," see Special Instructions, Part II, Line 4d, on page 3.)

b For each of the years included on line 9 of Part IV-A, attach a list showing the name of and the amount received from each pay (other than a "disqualified person") whose payments to the organization were more than $5,000. For this purpose, "payer" includes, but is not limited to, any organization described in sections 170(b)(1)(A)(i) thorugh (vi) and any government agency or bureau.

15

Indicate if your organization is one of the following. If so, complete the required schedule. (Submit only those schedules that apply to your organization. Do not submit blank schedules.)

  | Yes | No | If "Yes,"
complete
schedule:
Is the organization a church? |   | X | A
Is the organization, or any part of it, a school? |   | X | B
Is the organization, or any part of it, a hospital or medical research organizatoin? |   | X | C
Is the organization a section 509(a)(3) supporting organization? |   | X | D
Is the organization a private operating foundation? |   | X | E
Is the organization, or any part of it, a home for the aged or handicapped? |   | X | F
Is the organization, or any part of it, a child care organization? |   | X | G
Does the organization provide or administer any scholarship benefits, student aid, etc? |   | X | H
Has the organization take over, or will it take over, the facilites of a "for profit" institution? |   | X | I

Page 8

Part IV: Financial Data

Complete the financial statements for the current year and for each of the three years immediately before it. If in existence less than 4 years, complete the statements for each year in existence. If in existence less than 1 year; also provide proposed budgets for the 2 years following the current year.

A. Statement of Revenue and Expenses
R
E
V
E
N
U
E | | Current
tax year | 3 prior tax years or proposed budget for 2 years | (e) TOTAL
| (a) From 1/1/98
to 3/31/98 | (b) 1997 | (b) 1996 | (b) 1995
1 Gifts, grants, and contributions received (not including unusual grants- see pages 5 and 6 of the instructions) | 99.98 | 2,942.06 | 645.60 | 345.00 | 4,032.64
2 Membership fees received | 1,647.00 | 6,465.00 | 5,943.00 | 5,721.00 | 19,776.00
3 Gross investment income (see instructions for definition) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
4 Net income from organization's unrelated business activities not included on line 3. | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
5 Tax revenues levied for and either paid to or spent on behalf of the organization | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
6 Value of services or facilities furnished by a governmental unit to the organization without charge (not including the value of services or facilities generally furnished to the public without charge) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
7 Other income (not including gain or loss from sale of capital assets) (attach schedule) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
8 Total (add lines 1 through 7) | 1,746.98 | 9,407.06 | 6,588.60 | 6,066.00 | 23,808.64
9 Gross receipts from admissions, sales of merchandise or services, or furnishing facilities in any activity that is not an unrelated business within the meaning of section 513. Include related cost of sales on line 22. | 106.00 | 1,899.10 | 1,967.26 | 1,582.85 | 5,555.21
10 Total (add lines 8 and 9) | 1,852.98 | 11,306.16 | 8,555.86 | 7,648.85 | 29,363.85
11 Gain or loss from sale of capital assets (attach schedule) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
12 Unusual grants | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00
13 Total (add lines 10 through 12) | 1,852.98 | 11,306.16 | 8,555.86 | 7,648.85 | 29,363.85
E
X
P
E
N
S
E
S | 14 Fundraising expenses | 0.00 | 37.50 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
15 Contributions, gifts, grants, and similar amounts paid (attach schedule) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
16 Disbursements to or for benefit of members (attach schedule) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
17 Compensation of officers, directors, and trustees (attach schedule) | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
18 Other salaries and wages | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
19 Interest | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
20 Occupancy (rent, utilities, etc) | 1,879.89 | 7,975.96 | 5,244.46 | 4.316.49 |
21 Depreciation and depletion | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 | 0.00 |
22 Other (attach schedule) | 588.23 | 3,879.76 | 2,305.90 | 5,083.17 |
23 Total (add lines 14 through 22) | 2,468.12 | 11,893.22 | 7,550.81 | 9.399.66 |
24 Excess of revenue over expenses (line 13 minus line 23) | (618.14) | (587.06) | 1,005.50 | (1,750.81) |

Schedule of Other Expenses in 1998 (First Quarter)
Form 1023, Part IV, Section A, Item 22a

The following expenses incurred by Cyberspace Communications between 1/1/98 and 3/31/98 were reported in line 22a of form 1023, part IV, section A.

New Disk | 216.63
Excess Sales and Use Tax from 1997 | 143.83
Ethernet hub | 71.37
Renewal of cyberspace.org domain name | 50.00
Rental of P.O. Box for one year | 40.00
Backup Tapes | 36.09
Bank Service Charges | 30.31
TOTAL | 588.23

Schedule of Other Expenses in 1997
Form 1023, Part IV, Section A, Item 22b

The following expenses incurred by Cyberspace Communications between 1/1/97 and 12/31/97 were reported in line 22b of form 1023, part IV, section A.

Parts for New Computer (Sun 4/670) | 1399.60
2 ISDN Routers | 1150.93
Grex Shirts (for resale) | 736.60
Memory for Sun 4/670 | 248.00
Registration of grex.org domain name | 100.00
Bank Service Charges | 69.96
X-10 Interface Card | 40.98
Rental of P.O. Box for 1 year | 40.00
Backup Tapes | 28.49
Reservation of Park for Meeting | 24.00
New Chair | 21.20
Annual corporate filing fee | 10.00
Renewal of assumed name "Grex" | 10.00
TOTAL | 3879.76

Schedule of Other Expenses in 1996
Form 1023, Part IV, Section A, Item 22c

The following expenses incurred by Cyberspace Communications between 1/1/96 and 12/31/96 were reported in line 22c of form 1023, part IV, section A.

New Modems | 741.44
New Disk | 562.00
Misc. Computer Hardware | 400.00
Grex T-shirts (for resale) | 204.92
Bank service charges | 89.42
Misc. Moving Expenses | 69.30
JCC Table Rental | 60.00
Printing of Handbooks | 50.00
Renewal of domain name "cyberspace.org" | 50.00
Rental of P.O. Box for 1 year | 40.00
Annual corporate filing fee | 10.00
Lock and keys for computer room | 22.62
Annual corporate filing fee | 10.00
New Checks | 6.20
TOTAL | 2305.90

Schedule of Other Expenses in 1995
Form 1023, Part IV, Section A, Item 22d

The following expenses incurred by Cyberspace Communications between 1/1/95 and 12/31/95 were reported in line 22d of form 1023, part IV, section A.

New processor (Sun 4/260) and Modems | 1591.03
Misc. 4/260 Parts | 1143.07
Tape Drive & Moving Expenses | 734.49
New Disk | 500.00
Moving Expenses | 385.87
Rounter Components | 324.26
Misc. Compuer Hardware | 157.26
JCC Table Rental | 115.00
Bank Service Charges | 59.48
Keys and Modem Cables | 27.06
Corporate Filing Fee | 20.00
Corporate Registration Fee | 15.00
Keys | 12.75
TOTAL | 5070.42

Page 9

Part IV: Financial Data (Continued)

B. Balance Sheet (at end of the period shown) | Current tax year
Date 3/31/98
Assets | 1 | 2303.71
1 Cash
2 Accounts receivable, net | 2 | 0.00
3 Inventories | 3 | 384.10
4 Bonds and notes receivable (attach schedule) | 4 | 0.00
5 Corporate stocks (attach schedule) | 5 | 0.00
6 Mortgage loans (attach schedule) | 6 | 0.00
7 Other investments (attach schedule) | 7 | 0.00
8 Depreciable and depletable assets (attach schedule) | 8 | 3,850.00
9 Land | 9 | 0.00
10 Other assets (attach schedule) | 10 | 0.00
11 Total assets (add lines 1 through 10) | 11 | 6537.81
Liabilities | 12 | 0.00
12 Accounts payable
13 Contributions, gifts, grants, etc., payable | 13 | 0.00
14 Mortgages and notes payable (attach schedule) | 14 | 0.00
15 Other liabilities (attach schedule) | 15 | 0.00
16 Total liabilities (add lines 12 through 15) | 16 | 0.00
Fund Balances or Net Assets | 17 | 0.00
17 Total fund balances of net assets
18 Total liabilities and fund balances or net assets (add line 16 and line 17) | 18 | 6537.81

If there has been any substantial change in any aspect of the organization's financial activities since the end of the period shown above, check the box and attach a detailed explanation. > [ ]

Schedule of Depreciable and Depletable Assets
Form 1023, Part IV, Section B, Item 8

Cyberspace Communications has the following assets reported on line 8 of form 1023, part IV.B. The prices given are estimates based on recent market values of similar second-hand equipment, however much of this equipment is rather exotic and obsolete, and market prices vary widely.

Sun 4/670 computer (main Grex computer) | 1650.00
2 Ascend Pipeline P50 routers | 1000.00
2 Chase IOLan terminal servers | 800.00
15 modems | 75.00
Sun 4/370 computer parts | 50.00
Sun 4/260 computer (backup machine) | 25.00
Other computer parts and equipment | 200.00
Office furniture and tools | 50.00
TOTAL | 3850.00

Why Some Systems Can't Deliver Mail to Grex

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Although, in theory, internet standards ought to permit grex to receive mail from any site, in practice, there are sometimes reasons why we find it necessary to disable mail from a particular site. The following is a list of sites we've disabled; follow the link to learn more details. (Follow this link if you run one of these systems).

Some sites we don't like

ns3.ge.comtruely excessive mail bounces.
ivision.coloc.web.xara.net retries right away on class 400 errors.
jobserve.com - Jobserve Ltd. sends mail from non-deliverable address.
jobs.usweb.com - USWeb Corporation sends *lots* of mail to non-deliverable address.
netspace.org - Brown University student group - networking trouble.
hotmail.com - Hotmail Free Email - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
msn.com - Microsoft Network - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
mx1.expedia.com - Microsoft Corp. - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
didier.ee.gatech.edu - Georgia Institute of Technology - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
193.97.54.190 - lyndar.blr.novell.com - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
dns.cna.com - CNA Insurance - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
gateway.kellogg.com - Kellogg Company - is not RFC 1435 compliant.
bbmail1.unisys.com - we don't accept mail from here, because of a mail loop.
kmglmail.wipsys.soft.net - we don't accept mail from mailer-daemon@wipsys.soft.net, because it does not exist there.
mail.datasys.net - we don't accept mail from here, because aliens keep sending and resending 199609230951.FAA00296@mail.datasys.net.
moneyworld.com - spam.
natureplus.com - spam.
po*.wam.umd.edu - *@mobius.loop - we don't accept mail from owner-rage-l@mobius.loop, because it does not exist.
c2.net - endless mail to one of our users.
cybermirror1.com - misconfigured automatic mail response system.
seepz.tcs.co.in - bombarding user with full mailbox.
delhi.tcs.co.in - bad mailer configuration.
mail-gw.pacbell.net - defective anti-spam rule can be used to bombard random users.
dmshouston.net - does not accept mail from <>
qmail.erosmail.com - web server went insane
bali.infophil.com - no way to unsubscribe; seems to send spam

In addition, we don't accept mail from sites that appear to be dial-up IP connections, especially when we find that they are generating mass mail. There are too many of these sites to list here, look at

/usr/adm/badsys
  

on grex to learn about them.

If you administer any of the above systems, and want to fix the problem, you must also send mail to us to have us re-enable mail service.

In the past, we had a lot of problems with sites that had the in RFC 1435 problem. Here's a list of sites that had this problem (a long time ago).

146.174.250.100 noping, worf.qntm.com (HP)
152.163.200.7   noping, no incoming smtp (=listmail.aol.com)
198.93.152.11   noping, adeskgate.autodesk.com (SMI-5.3)
200.13.16.8     noping, no incoming smtp (=NIC.DATA.NET.MX, no rev arpa)
204.144.158.25  noping, puck.solbourne.com MS IE Connector
204.70.138.39   noping, neptune.pcy.mci.net Sendmail 8.6.12
205.229.27.7    noping, no incoming smtp (no rev arpa, =uunet technologies, inc.)
206.215.36.2    noping, no incoming smtp (no rev arpa, =Southern California College)
207.1.151.75    noping, no incoming smtp (h-207-1-151-75.netscape.com)

An earlier version of the mail quota software on grex rejected mail with SMTP error 452, which told the remote mail software to try again later. (SMTP is described in RFC 821.) Some mail systems interpreted later to be a few seconds later, which would cause endless problems on grex. We added a bunch of systems to badsys to deal with this. We then noticed that people whose mailboxes filled up didn't seem to appreciate the fact we were holding mail off for them. So we have become much more hard-assed. If someone's mailbox fills up, we now generate an SMTP 552 error, which causes the remote mail software to give up right away. End of problem.

Here is a list of sites that had this problem:

lists.xmission.com
sirius.ctr.columbia.edu
kira.intranet.org
biff.kiva.net
listserv.NoDak.edu
mailnfs0.tiac.net
suntan.tandem.com
geek-gw.ptw.com
inet-user-gw-1.us.oracle.com

These sites used to have a problem, but it appears to be resolved now.

charis.berean.org       resolved Nov 1996; thanks to chris@oz.kis.net
kingcrab.informix.com   resolved Jan 1997; thanks to dgoebel@informix.com
blueshift.com   resolved 18 Mar 1997; thanks to John Ingram <john@blueshift.com>
netspace.org    resolved ?; thanks to bfisk@netspace.org

c2.net - Community ConneXion

We don't receive mail from this site, apparently because it was originating an endless stream of mail to a user on grex. This was done 31 March 1997.

moneyworld.com - Financial Connections, Inc

natureplus.com - NetAmerica USA

We don't receive mail from these sites, because they kept sending us spam to forward to the rest of the internet, even after being asked not to do this. Grex does not have the resources to act as any sort of mail relay station, let alone one for spam.

I don't belive that email to Bob Williams works. Perhaps you can reach him at(206) 269-0846? Here's his address:

2508 5th Ave, #104
Seattle, WA 98121

cybermirror1.com - Cyber Promotions

We don't receive mail from this site, because something claiming to be an automatic mail response system sent mail to MAILER-DAEMON@cyberspace.org on 2 August 1997. This mail address does not correspond to a human, and would only be used on bounce messages generated by grex. It is a serious flaw for an automatic mail response system to reply to a bounce message that was most probably triggered by earlier mail sent by the automatic mail response system.

msn.com - Microsoft Network

Mail that is sent from Microsoft Network, appears (to us) to orginate from a series of machine named upsmot01.msn.com, upsmot02.msn.com, upsmot03.msn.com, etc. Although these machines all implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, they live behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from these machines do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

We contacted Microsoft on 17 April 1996, but were unsuccessful in correcting the problem. To contact the people in charge of the outbound SMTP gateways at Microsoft Network, send mail to David Whipple <dwhipple@microsoft.com> and postmaster@msn.com, or write to

David Whipple
One Microsoft Way
Redmond, WA 98052-6399
USA

mx1.expedia.com - Microsoft Corp.

Mail that is sent from Microsoft expedia travel services, appears (to us) to orginate from a series of machine named mx1.expedia.com, etc. Although these machines all implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, they live behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from these machines do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

We contacted Microsoft on 21 March 1997, but were unsuccessful in correcting the problem. To contact the people in charge of the outbound SMTP gateways at Microsoft Network, send mail to David Whipple <dwhipple@microsoft.com> and postmaster@msn.com, or write to

David Whipple
One Microsoft Way
Redmond, WA 98052-6399
USA

lyndar.blr.novell.com - Novell, Inc.

The machine at IP address 137.97.54.190 appears to implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, but lives behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from this machine do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

This host, 137.65.2.254, also does not have a valid DNS in-addr.arpa PTR record. This would not affect mail delivery, but is a curious omission.

We sent a message on 19 March 1997 to postmaster@blr.novell.com but were unsuccessful in getting any response. We also tried contacting Sean Gilkes <sgilkes@novell.com>, Peter Dennis Bartok <Peter_Dennis_Bartok@Novell.DE>, and Mark Richardson <mark_richardson@NOVELL.COM> but these turned out to be invalid addresses. Perhaps it would be worth sending paper mail to:

Novell GmbH
Monschauer Str. 12
D-40549 Duesseldorf
Germany

dns.cna.com - CNA Insurance

The machine dns.cna.com (159.10.4.25) appears to implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, but lives behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from this machine do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

We sent a message on 25 March 1997 to postmaster@sch1p116.cna.com, and root@sch1p116.cna.com, but were unsuccessful in getting any response (as of 27 March 1997). We also tried contacting David Hillman <david.hillman@cna.com> with no more luck. In fact, David Hillman <david.hillman@cna.com> turned out to be an invalid mail address. Perhaps it would be worth sending paper mail to:

CNA Plaza
Chicago, IL 60685
USA

gateway.kellogg.com - Kellogg Company

The machine gateway.kellogg.com (198.108.149.2) appears to implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, but lives behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from this machine do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

We sent a message on 25 March 1997 to postmaster@gateway.kellogg.com but were unsuccessful in getting any response (as of 27 March 1997). We also tried contacting Dave Gibson <dave.gibson@kellogg.com>, and Vinh Tran <vinh-chi.tran@kellogg.com>, with no more luck. In fact, Dave Gibson <dave.gibson@kellogg.com>, and Vinh Tran <vinh-chi.tran@kellogg.com>, turned out to be invalid mail addresses. Perhaps it would be worth sending paper mail to:

Kellogg Company
235 Porter Street
Battle Creek, MI 49017
USA

didier.ee.gatech.edu - Georgia Institute of Technology

The machine didier.ee.gatech.edu appears to implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, but lives behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from this machine do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

We sent a message to postmaster@ee.gatech.edu on 21 March 1997, but were unsuccessful in getting any response. It may also be possible to contact the appropriate: people by writing:

Office of Computing Services
258 Fourth Street, Rich Building
Atlanta, GA 30332
USA

ivision.coloc.web.xara.net

This host retries right away when our mail returns a 400 class error. This is wrong, and wastes CPU and network bandwidth on our end. The retry rate should be more like once every 30 minutes, with some sort of exponential backoff algorithm. We haven't contacted xara.net yet, as of 14-Dec-1997.

ns3.ge.com - General Electric Company.

This host is generating a truely excessive number of bounces. A lot of mail seems to be going to sachinvt@cyberspace.org. This mail is apparently being sent from <Sachin.Thakur@gepex.ge.com>. This has been going on for 7 days, since 4-Oct-1999, and is taking up a lot of our network bandwidth. C'mon, guys, do you *really* need to do this?

jobserve.com - Jobserve Ltd.

We don't accept mail from nobody@deliver-5.tiptree.jobserve.com because, if it cannot be delivered on grex, the bounce message can't be returned to the originating agent.

jobs.usweb.com - USWeb Corporation

We don't accept mail from this system, because the mailer at this site appears to be broken, and was bombarding us with tons of mail for a non-existant address on 17 May 1997.

hotmail.com - Hotmail Free Email

Mail that is sent from Hotmail, appears (to us) to orginate from a series of machine named F5.hotmail.com, F19.hotmail.com, F25.hotmail.com, etc.

Although these machines all implement RFC 1191 path MTU discovery, they live behind a firewall that does not pass any ICMP traffic through. Because of this, TCP connections from these machines do not manage to pass complete e-Mail messages to grex, and instead hang around consuming network bandwith and computing resources on grex until they timeout. This problem is explicitly described in RFC 1435, and in that RFC, the authors recommend that such firewalls should be modified to pass ICMP message Type 3 Code 4 messages.

We have informed Hotmail (postmaster@hotmail.com) on 13 March 1997.

Some additional contact points, if you would like to contact them, are Joshua Goldsmith <joshin@HOTMAIL.COM>, at phone number (408) 222-7005 ext. 154., and Jack Smith <jsmith@HOTMAIL.COM>, at phone number (408) 222-7000.

Javasoft
1290 Oakmead Parkway
Suite 218
Sunnyvale, CA 94086
USA

kmglmail.wipsys.wipsys.soft.net.

We don't accept mail from mailer-daemon@wipsys.soft.net if sent from this address, because if it cannot be delivered on grex, it can't be returned to wipsys.

po*.wam.umd.edu - *@mobius.loop

We don't accept mail from owner-rage-l@mobius.loop (or any other mobius.loop address) because if it cannot be delivered on grex, it can't be returned to knot.org.

mail.datasys.net - DSS Online

There appears to be a problem, perhaps temporary in nature, that had resulted in multiple copies of a message with message-ID 199609230951.FAA00296@mail.datasys.net being sent to grex. This is very bad, and had filled up one person's mailbox.

We have informed postmaster@mail.datasys.net on Wednesday, 25 September 1996 00:30 -400, but never received any reply.

Some additional contact points, if you would like to contact them, are administrator@MAIL.DATASYS.NET, at phone number (912) 241-0607.

2300 Madison Highway
Valdosta, GA 31603
USA

bbmail1.unisys.com - Unisys Corporation

There is a mail loop between sureshv@tulblr.unisys.com and sureshv@nether.net. Mail from sureshv@tulblr.unisys.com is forwarded to grex as well as nether.net. The result is that about 5-6 copies of every message sent to sureshv@tulblr.unisys.com are shipped to grex, and the last one comes with too many RFC 822 "Received:" timestamps so is sent to postmaster@cyberspace.org instead. We, the people who read postmaster mail on grex, really don't want sureshv's private mail. We contacted both Informix and Nether.net on 12 October 1997, but never received any response (as of 16 January, 1997).

To contact the people in charge at unisys, you might try sending mail to Chris Liebsack, the technical and zone contact for unisys.com, or postmaster@unisys.com . It is also possible to send US postal mail to

Unisys Corporate Headquarters
Blue Bell, PA 19424-0001
U.S.A.

To contact the people in charge at nether.net, you might try sending mail to Jared Mauch, Jared Mauch also has a FAX telephone number, 313-998-6105. It is also possible to send US postal mail to

Nether Network
3015 Whisperwood Dr. #261
Ann Arbor, MI 48105
USA

Good luck. We received no response from these e-mail addresses.

seepz.tcs.co.in - ?

We don't accept mail from this system for user kanni@cyberspace.org (or any other user). because the mailer at this site was attempting to connect to us every few seconds to deliver mail, and his mailbox was full. Reversa arpa does not work for this host; we are not sure exactly what this host is for, or who uses it. Also, this host is sending mail that claims to be from the mailbox that filled up on grex; this seems like a really bad thing.

delhi.tcs.co.in - ?

We don't accept mail from this system because the mailer at this site was broken on 29 March 1998. The mail software on this system generated a mail address consisted entirely of non-ascii characters. When grex tried to send mail to this address, it got these errors:

554 Infinite loop in ruleset 3, rule 12
554 Infinite loop in ruleset 3, rule 12

mail-gw.pacbell.net - Pacific Bell Internet Services

We don't accept mail from this system because the mailer at this site has a defective anti-spam rule. The intent of this rule appears to be to prevent this host from being used to relay mail. Unfortunately, this rule is implemented in the wrong place. Instead of rejecting mail before it is accepted, it is accepted, queued, rejected, and bounced. The bounce message is not delivered to the originating host, which may be long gone, but instead to the return path, which may be a completely different host, and point to the mailbox of a user who is completely not associated with the problem. Very bad.

2 Mar 1998 - added to badsys.

bali.infophil.com - InfoPhil, Inc.

We don't accept mail from this system because this system keeps sending mail to several addresses on grex despite our best efforts to remove those addresses from the supposed mailing list sent from here. The mail that is sent also appears to contain a large amount of commercial content, sugggesting that this is actually thinly disguised unsolicited commercial e-mail, or spam. We followed the directions given to unsubscribe rbk@cyberspace.org on 16 Feb 1999, with no luck.

6 Nov 1999 - added to badsys.

dmshouston.net - Networks On-Line

We don't accept mail from this system because the mailer at this site does not accept bounce messages from grex. According to RFC 821 in section 3.6 (page 14), when a mail rejection notice is generated, the return path is supposed to be <>. However, when this mail is returned to dmshouston.net, this mail is rejected with the message

>>> MAIL From:<>
<<< 501 bogus mail from
554 <ThoughtADay-owner@ThoughtADay.com>... Remote protocol error

This is bad.

1 Oct 1998 - added to badsys.

qmail.erosmail.com - TropiX Talent

We don't accept mail from this system because the mailer at this site had been sending mail to an invalid address at grex for some time, and when we attempted to unsubscribe this address, their web server went insane. Apparently, it went into some sort of infinite redirect loop, and attempted to unsubscribe kelvin@cyberspace.org a whole *bunch* of times. Each attempt resulted in generating mail to kelvin. By the time we noticed, and turned off the temporary alias, over one megabyte of unsubscribe reports had been sent. Their mailer is still busy attempting to send more such reports.

Proper mailing list software notices when mail sent to invalid addresses is rejected with "no such user", and proper web software does not return redirect pages pointing to itself.

16 Feb 1999 - added to badsys.

alpha2.dlinc.com - D & L Online, Inc

We don't accept mail from this system because it sends mail as <nobody@dlinc.com>, and if a bounce notification is sent to this address, the mailer for the dlinc.com domain rejects this. According to RFC 821 in section 3.6 (page 14), when a mail rejection notice is generated, the return path is supposed to be <>. However, when this mail is returned to alpha1.dlinc.com (the MX host for the dlinc.com domain), this mail is rejected with the message

>>> MAIL From:<>
<<< 550 <>... Sender address not in proper format
554 <nobody@dlinc.com>... Remote protocol error

This is bad. (Sending messages as nobody seems most dubious in the first place.)

15 Mar 1999 - added to badsys.

internet standards - some pointers

ICMP is an integral and necessary part of the TCP/IP protocol stack. It is used for MTU path discovery, various kinds of IP layer congestion control, TCP error returns, and network diagnostic software. Without ICMP, some or all of these will not work. Grex is unusual in that its internet connection tends to fragment packets, which can cause problems with non-compliant internet implementations or sites. Nevertheless, IP fragmentation is, in fact, part of the standard, and sites that can't handle IP fragmentation are not completely in compliance.

For more information on internet host requirements, check out RFC 1122 and RFC 1123, Requirements for Internet Hosts. For information on TCP, check out RFC 793 and RFC 964. For information on ICMP, check out RFC 792 and RFC 950. ICMP and TCP are layered on top of IP, which is described in RFC 791. For information on path MTU discovery, check out RFC 1191. SMTP (the mail transport protocol used by grex for incoming mail) is described in RFC 821 and RFC 822. RFC 1435 contains IESG advice on path MTU discovery. RFC 1858 talks about security considerations for IP fragment filtering. RFC 1470 contains a list of tools that can be used to debug TCP/IP networks.

The IETF standards process is described in RFC 1796 and RFC 1818. Some of the philosophy behind the internet can be found in RFC 722, RFC 871, RFC 875, RFC 1118, and RFC 1539. When grex refuses mail for hosts described in this http document, it is, in essence, implementing a greatly updated form of the administrative denial of service described in RFC 706.

There are many RFC's that deal with security issues. RFC 1244 contains a general site security handbook. RFC 1636 contains workshop notes on internet security.

For more general internet information, check out RFC 1206 - new internet user, and RFC 1207 - experienced internet user. RFC 1392 contains an internet glossary. Finally, RFC 1855 contains a netiquette guide.

This is merely a starter list of relevant RFC's; for a complete list of RFC's, check out the RFC index file.

Contact Information

www.cyberspace.org + postmaster@cyberspace.org

$Id: badsys.xhtml 1438 2014-03-23 16:39:04Z kentn $

Grex's Declaration of Principles

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

This system is intended to foster community education and the
    spiritual and intellectual enrichment of its users through
    the peaceable interchange of ideas.

The members of this system hope to attract a large, diverse, and
    mature group of thinking individuals and thereby to contribute
    to a better-informed citizenry.

Governance of the system is based on cooperative principles,
    including open membership, democratic control, and non-
    profit economics.

This is an open-access system; the public is welcome.  However,
    regular users are encouraged to become members and help
    support the system financially.  Voting on system policy
    matters is restricted to members.

It should go without saying that the system is specifically NOT
    intended for any illegal purpose.

Users are asked to be considerate of others, and are especially
    asked to make a point of setting a good example for those
    few who may from time to time fail to return the favor.

$Id: principles.xhtml 1438 2014-03-23 16:39:04Z kentn $

Information about Cyberspace Communications

Home
About Us
Get a Free Account
FAQ
Become a Member
Contact Us

Cyberspace Communications is a non-profit, tax-exempt corporation which provides a computer conferencing system, called Grex, to the public, for free.

Cyberspace Communications functions as an online democracy, with policies set by its users. Formally, we are governed by a board of directors elected by our members, but we have a tradition of operating very much by a consensus. Topics are always publicly discussed in the Co-op conference before being voted on by the board, and the board is very reluctant to decide on anything until a strong consensus has emerged in the conference. In addition, any member can call a vote by the membership on any subject, and the board has no power to overrule the results of such votes. Changes to the bylaws can only be made by votes of the membership.

Day-to-day administration of Grex is performed by the Grex staff, whose members are appointed by the board. Like the board members, all staff members are volunteers.

Mailing Address:

Cyberspace Communications, Inc.
P.O. Box 4432
Ann Arbor, MI 48106-4432, USA.

Cyberspace Communications Document Archive:

Articles of Incorporation
Bylaws
Application for 501(c)3 Tax-Exempt Status
IRS Determination Letter for 501(c)3 Tax-Exempt Status
Current Board of Directors
Current Staff Members
Co-Op BBS Conference (policy discussions)
Minutes of Past Board Meetings
Results of Past Membership Votes
Log of Policy Decisions
Lawsuit: Cyberspace vs Engler

$Id: index.xhtml 1468 2014-04-15 12:53:01Z kentn $ We welcome your feedback.